Aseef Ahmed 12/5/2016

# **ASEEF AHMED**

# Sr. Software Engineer & System Administrator

**Address:** 81/83, Road-4, Block-B, Niketon, Gulshan, Dhaka-1212 **Mobile:** 0199-223-6479

Email: contact@aseefahmed.net

Web: aseefahmed.net

#### **About Myself**

I am Zend Certified PHP Engineer (ZCPE) and fluent in English having more tha 9 years of working experience in web industry as a Sr. Engineer. My vission is to gain confidence and fame using my potential in the field of Web Development, and express my innovative creative skills for myself and my company.

#### **Employment**

#### Fair Pattern Inc. (A USA Based Company)

**2015 - Present** 

Sr. Software Engineer

Building a social networking for entrepreneur in Laravel. Responsible for working on a range of projects and interacting on a daily basis with graphic designers, other talented back-end developers and QA Team. Worked as part of a multi-disciplinary team, carrying out ad-hoc tasks as requested by the IT Manager. Had daily meeting to ensure the application build for customer's precisely matched their requirements

#### **Nexus Web Consultancy Ltd.**

2010 - 2015

Sr. Web Developer

- Developing and maintaining the front end functionality of websites
- Participating in discussions with clients to clarify what they want.
- Designing prototypes for apps and websites
- Creating logos, banners and buttons for web sites.
- Writing cross browser compliant XHTML, CSS & JavaScript
- Simultaneously managing several databases and reporting tools
- Provide guidance to other team members on web development issues.
- Developing websites that have a consistent feel and look throughout all web properties
- Providing technical support to end users.
- Identifying and correcting software deficiencies
- Devising SEO strategies based around specific keywords

#### BJIT Ltd.(Bangladesh-Japan IT)

2008 - 2009

**Professional Certification** 

Engineer (ZCPE)



**Professional Course** 

Red Hat Linux 00000 CCNA

**Programming Skills** 

PHP ..... Laravel Framework MySQL CSS **Bootstrap** Ruby on Rails C# ASP.NET 

## **Javascript Skills**

**Javascript JQuery** React.JS Node.IS Angular.JS 

#### **Database Skills**

MySQL MongoDB **SOL Server** 

# **English Proficiency**

PHP Developer

12/5/2016 Aseef Ahmed

My main responsibility is building flexible, modular and well tested JavaScript/HTMI/CSS based applications. Some of them require real time communication, so I have the luck to work with various Javascript frameworks. Along with that I'm using node to improve and speed up my workflow. Coding cross-browser web sites, I'm happy to say that I produce responsive apps.

IFI TS - 7.5

#### **Evoknow (A USA Based Software Firm)**

2006 - 2008

Web Developer

As a web developer I had to work as a team member to develop robus web applicatio based on PHP, Javascript, CSS and many other Javascript frameworks along with MVC Framework.

## Amazon

Payment Gateways Google 00000 Facebook 

#### Remarkable Projects

This is the Pay-roll System application in asp.net. Here there are two kinds of customers administration and worker. Employee can only see the information and his transaction per month. Admin can get into worker information, worker wage information, keep information and can also modify and remove those information. Employee can send email to administration using this application, since it is web based application. Since employees have individual name and private password it is properly secured. [ASP.NET Project]

www.deltanettravel.gr: Deltanet is a destionation management website that helps to manage tourist services, in Greece. You can really see different features on this website, so smooth browsing. [Laravel Project, React.]s, Mysql, Git, JIRA]

www.fusioninvoice.com: With FusionInvoice you can launch your own selfhosted invoicing platform that you can use to keep track of your monetary situation within your business, all within a beautiful interface [Laravel Project, JQuery, Ajax., Mysql, Git]

### **Operating System**

Twitter

**Third Party API** 

Linux Mac Windows 

### **Education**

# **Computer Science & Engineering (CSE)**

Jahangirnagar University CGPA: 3.21 (Out of 4)

2001 - 2005

2009 - 2010

### **Masters in Business Administration (MBA)**

University of Wales

Result: 60%

# **Version Control System**

Git . . . . . . . . Gitbub.com BitBucket.org 

#### **Project Management Tools**

lira Microsoft Office 2010

#### **Graphical Tools**

Photoshop 000000

**WEB**: www.aseefahmed.net

2/2 http://aseefahmed.net/cv.php